rip.ie 2017-11-14

# RIP.IE PRIVACY POLICY

**RIP.IE PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Gradam Communications Limited trading as RIP.ie, (" **We** " or “ **RIP.ie** ”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This statement (together with our [terms and conditions](http://www.rip.ie/article.php?AID=90)  and [cookie policy](http://www.rip.ie/article.php?AID=92) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. 

For the purpose of the Data Protection Acts, 1988 and 2003 (the **Acts** ), the data controller is Gradam Communications Limited trading as RIP.ie a company incorporated in Ireland with company number 410080 whose registered office is at Killin View, Court Road, Deer Park, Dundalk, Co. Louth.

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By using our website [www.RIP.ie](http://www.rip.ie/) and its subdomains and mobile versions (our “ **Site** ”) you indicate your acceptance of this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree to this Privacy Statement, do not use or access the Site.

**1.      ****INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT**

We may collect and process the following data:

·                          **Information you give us.** Information that is provided by you to us via email; phone; fax; through our Site; or by any other means. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number. If any person contacts us via phone, email, post, fax, through our Site or otherwise, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

·                          **Information we collect about you.** With regard to each of your visits to our Site we may automatically collect the following information:

·         technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; and

·         information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our Site (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.

This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

·                          **Information we receive from other sources**. We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. In this case we will have informed you when we collected that data that it may be shared internally and combined with data collected on this Site. We also work closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

**2.      ****USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION**

We use information collected in the following ways:

·                          Where you provide information to us we may use this:

·         To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

·         To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or to provide you with information about other services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about.

·         To notify you about changes to our service.

·         To ensure that content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

·         We may also provide third parties with aggregate information about our users that does not identify them.

·                          Where we collect information about you we may use this:

·         To administer our Site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes.

·         To improve our Site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

·         To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

·         As part of our efforts to keep our Site safe and secure.

·         To measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you.

·         To make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Site about goods or services that may interest you or them.

·                          Where we receive information from other sources we may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may us this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

**3.      ****DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

Your personal information may be disclosed in the following ways:

·                          We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 155 of the Companies Acts, 1963. The reason for this disclosure includes, but is not limited to, enabling one of our related companies to perform certain services on our behalf.

·                          Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you. Where we work with a business partner in collecting your data, they are the data controller and you will be made aware that we are acting on their behalf. In that case we are the data processors of that data and we will not keep it but will transfer your data to the business partner that we work for.

·                          In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

·                          If RIP.ie or a substantial part of its assets are acquired by a third party personal data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets.

·                          Where advertising is displayed on our Site we may disclose data to advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others.  We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that 500 men aged under 30 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in Dublin). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience.

·                          Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Site.

·                          If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of RIP.ie, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

·                          Where you give us permission to do so.

**4.      ****WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers and we take the security of the data that we store seriously. However, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**5.      ****USER RIGHTS**

Users have the right to ask us not to process personal data for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect user data, unsubscribing via the link on any marketing email you receive from us or by contacting us at [info@rip.ie](mailto:info@rip.ie). You can also ask us to correct any data we hold about you that you think may be incorrect.

Our Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**6.      ****ACCESS TO INFORMATION**

The Acts gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Acts. Any access request may be subject to a fee of €6.35 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

**7.      ****CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Any changes we may make to our privacy statement in the future will be posted on this page. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this statement.

**8.      ****CONTACT**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy statement are welcomed and should be addressed to [info@rip.ie](mailto:info@rip.ie).

 Communications Limited trading as RIP.ie, (" **We** ") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This policy (together with our [terms and conditions](http://rip.ie/article.php?AID=90) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 (the **Acts** ), the data controller is Gradam Communications Limited trading as RIP.ie a company incorporated in Ireland with company number 410080 whose registered office is at Philipstown, Dundalk, County Louth.

**INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT**

We may collect and process the following data:

·                          Information that is provided by any person filling in forms on our site rip.ie ( **our site** ).

·                          If any person contacts us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

·                          Details of visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required

for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that are accessed by users.

**IP ADDRESSES**

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

**COOKIES**

Please see our cookie policy for information on how we use cookies.

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. However, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

·                          To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

·                          To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us.

·                          To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.

·                          To notify you about changes to our service.

·                          We may also provide third parties with aggregate information about our users that does not identify them.

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 155 of the Companies Acts, 1963.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

·                          In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

·                          If Gradam Communications Limited trading as RIP.ie or a substantial part of its assets (including by way of an example are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

·                          If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions of Use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Gradam Communications Limited trading as RIP.ie, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

·                          Where you give us permission to do so.

**USER RIGHTS**

Users have the right to ask us not to process personal data for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect user data. Users can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [info@rip.ie](mailto:info@rip.ie).

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**ACCESS TO INFORMATION**

The Acts gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Acts. Any access request may be subject to a fee of €6.35 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, may be notified to you by e-mail.

**CONTACT**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [info@rip.ie](mailto:info@rip.ie).
